RG 062:093, Town of New Haven
Connecticut State Library
Town of New Haven records
1795-1953
Connecticut State Library
New Haven (Conn.)
75 cubic feet
Administrative and tax records for the town of New Haven.
RG062_093
Multiple
Historical Note
The town of New Haven was settled in April 1638, named in August 1640 and incorporated in 1784. The town and city consolidated in November 1895.
Scope and Content
Administrative and tax records for the town of New Haven.
Index Terms
Subjects:
Tax assessment -- Connecticut -- New Haven -- Registers; Taxation -- Connecticut -- New Haven -- Registers; Local taxation -- Connecticut -- New Haven -- Registers; Property tax -- Connecticut -- New Haven -- Registers; Fire insurance -- Connecticut -- New Haven -- Maps; Buildings -- Connecticut -- New Haven -- Maps
Places:
New Haven (Conn.) -- Records and correspondence; New Haven (Conn.) -- Maps; New Haven (Conn.) -- Buildings, structures, etc. -- Maps
Restrictions on Access
These records are stored at an off-site facility and therefore may not be available on a same-day basis.
See the policy.
Container List
- Records, 1795-1953
  - T000229
    - Tax abstracts
      Volumes for 1880 to 1899 are not boxed.
      - 1795, 1808, 1809 (Box Box 1)
      - 1811, 1812, 1814 (Box Box 2)
      - 1815, 1816, 1817, 1819 (Box Box 3)
      - 1824, 1825, 1826, 1828, 1829 (Box Box 4)
      - 1830, 1831, 1832, 1833, 1834 (Box Box 5)
      - 1835, 1836, 1837, 1838, 1839 (Box Box 6)
      - 1840, 1841, 1842 (Box Box 7)
      - 1843 (Box Box 8)
      - 1844, 2 volumes (Box Box 8)
      - 1846 (Box Box 9)
      - 1847, 2 volumes (Box Box 9)
      - 1848, 1849 (Box Box 10)
      - First School District, 1849 (Box Box 10)
      - Unidentified, undated (Box Box 10)
        This volume has no cover.
      - Fair Haven Fire Association, 1850 (Box Box 11)
      - First School Society, 1850 (Box Box 11)
      - Assessments, 1850 (Box Box 11)
      - Fair Haven Fire Association, 1851 (Box Box 12)
      - First School Society, 1851 (Box Box 12)
      - Assessments, 1851 (Box Box 12)
      - First School Society, 1852 (Box Box 13)
      - Assessments, 1852 (Box Box 13)
      - Fair Haven Fire Association, 1853 (Box Box 14)
      - First School Society, 1853 (Box Box 14)
      - Assessments, 1853 (Box Box 14)
      - Fair Haven Fire Association, 1854 (Box Box 15)
      - First School Society, 1854 (Box Box 15)
      - Assessments, 1854 (Box Box 15)
      - Fair Haven Fire Association, 1855 (Box Box 16)
      - First School Society, 1855 (Box Box 16)
      - Assessments, 1855 (Box Box 16)
      - Fair Haven School District, 1856 (Box Box 17)
      - First School Society, 1856 (Box Box 17)
      - Assessments, 1856 (Box Box 17)
      - Assessments, 1857 (Box Box 18)
      - School District, 1858 (Box Box 19)
      - Assessments, 1858 (Box Box 19)
      - Fair Haven Fire Association, 1859 (Box Box 20)
      - School District, 1859 (Box Box 20)
      - Assessments, 1859 (Box Box 20)
      - Assessments, 1860 (Box Box 21)
      - Westville School District, 1861 (Box Box 22)
      - Fair Haven Fire Association and Fair Haven School District, 1861 (Box Box 22)
      - School District, 1861 (Box Box 22)
      - Assessments, 1861 (Box Box 22)
      - School District, 1862 (Box Box 23)
      - Assessments, 1862 (Box Box 23)
      - Westville School District, 1863 (Box Box 24)
      - School District, 1863 (Box Box 24)
      - Assessments, 1863 (Box Box 24)
      - School District, 1864 (Box Box 25)
      - Assessments, 1864 (Box Box 25)
      - Westville School District, 1865 (Box Box 26)
      - Fair Haven School Association, 1865 (Box Box 26)
      - School District, 1865 (Box Box 26)
      - Assessments, 1865 (Box Box 26)
      - Westville School District, 1866 (Box Box 27)
      - School District, 1866 (Box Box 27)
      - Assessments, 1866 (Box Box 27)
      - Westville School District, 1867 (Box Box 28)
      - Fair Haven School Association, 1867 (Box Box 28)
      - School District, 1867 (Box Box 28)
      - Assessments, 1867 (Box Box 28)
      - Westville School District, 1868 (Box Box 29)
      - Fair Haven School District, 1868 (Box Box 29)
      - School District, 1868 (Box Box 29)
      - Assessments, 1868 (Box Box 29)
      - Westville School District, 1869 (Box Box 30)
      - School District, 1869 (Box Box 30)
      - Assessments, 1869 (Box Box 30)
      - Westville School District, 1870 (Box Box 31)
      - Fair Haven School District, 1870 (Box Box 31)
      - School District, 1870 (Box Box 31)
      - Assessments, 1870 (Box Box 31)
      - Westville School District, 1871 (Box Box 32)
      - Fair Haven School District, 1871 (Box Box 32)
      - School District, 1871 (Box Box 32)
      - Assessments, 1871 (Box Box 32)
      - Westville School District, 1872 (Box Box 33)
      - City School District, 1872 (Box Box 33)
      - Assessments, 1872 (Box Box 33)
      - Westville School District, 1873 (Box Box 34)
      - Fair Haven School District, 1873 (Box Box 34)
      - City School District, 1873 (Box Box 34)
      - Assessments, 1873 (Box Box 34)
      - Westville School District, 1874 (Box Box 35)
      - City School District, 1874 (Box Box 35)
      - Assessments, 1874 (Box Box 35)
      - Westville School District, 1875 (Box Box 36)
      - School District, 1875 (Box Box 36)
      - Assessments, 1875 (Box Box 36)
      - Westville School District, 1876 (Box Box 37)
      - School District, 1876 (Box Box 37)
      - Assessments, 1876 (Box Box 37)
      - Westville School District, 1877 (Box Box 38)
      - School District, 1877 (Box Box 38)
      - Assessments, 1877 (Box Box 38)
      - Westville School District, 1878 (Box Box 39)
      - School District, 1878 (Box Box 39)
      - Assessments, 1878 (Box Box 39)
      - Westville School District, 1879 (Box Box 40)
      - School District, 1879 (Box Box 40)
      - Assessments, 1879 (Box Box 40)
      - Grand List, 1880; 2 volumes
      - School District, 1880; 1 volume
      - Westville School District, 1881; 1 volume
      - School District, 1881; 1 volume
      - Grand List, 1881; 1 volume
      - Westville School District, 1882; 1 volume
      - School District, 1882; 1 volume
      - Westville School District, 1883; 1 volume
      - School District, 1883; 1 volume
      - Grand List, 1883; 1 volume
      - Westville School District, 1884; 1 volume
      - School District, 1884; 1 volume
      - Grand List, 1884; 1 volume
      - Westville School District, 1885; 1 volume
      - School District, 1885; 1 volume
      - Grand List, 1885; 1 volume
      - Westville School District, 1886; 1 volume
      - School District, 1886; 1 volume
      - Grand List, 1886; 1 volume
      - Westville School District, 1887; 1 volume
      - School District, 1887; 1 volume
      - Grand List, 1887; 1 volume
      - Westville School District, 1888; 1 volume
      - School District, 1888; 1 volume
      - Grand List, 1888; 1 volume
      - School District, 1889; 1 volume
      - Grand List, 1889; 1 volume
      - Westville School District, 1890; 1 volume
      - School District, 1890; 1 volume
      - Grand List, 1890; 1 volume
      - Westville School District, 1891; 1 volume
      - School District, 1891; 1 volume
      - Grand List, 1891; 1 volume
      - Westville School District, 1892; 1 volume
      - School District, 1892; 1 volume
      - Grand List, 1892; 1 volume
      - Westville School District, 1893; 1 volume
      - School District, 1893; 1 volume
      - Grand List, 1893; 1 volume
      - Westville School District, 1894; 1 volume
      - School District, 1894; 1 volume
      - Grand List, 1894; 1 volume
      - Westville School District, 1895; 1 volume
      - School District, 1895; 1 volume
      - Grand List, 1895; 1 volume
      - Westville School District, 1896; 1 volume
      - School District, 1896; 1 volume
      - Grand List, 1896; 1 volume
      - Westville School District, 1897; 1 volume
      - Annex and West of Dixwell Avenue, 1897; 1 volume
      - School District, 1897; 1 volume
      - Grand List, 1897; 1 volume
      - Westville School District, 1898; 1 volume
      - Grand List, 1898; 1 volume
      - Westville School District, 1899; 1 volume
      - Grand List, 1899; 1 volume
      - Unidentified, 2 partial volumes (Box Box 41)
    - Street books, undated; 3 volumes (Box Box 42)
    - Street books, undated; 3 volumes (Box Box 43)
    - Tax Collector's workbook, undated (Box Box 44)
    - Record of expenditures, 1899-1902 (Box Box 44)
      Includes amounts paid by Board of Assessors, Registrar of Vital Statistics and Town Clerk.
    - List of collections for licenses and permits, 1953 (Box Box 44)
    - List of old age assistance tax abatements and exemptions, 1935-1944 (Box Box 44)
    - Census book, 1833 (Box Box 44)
    - Isaac Auger land deed from James C. Thomas, 1832 January 12 (Box Box 44)
    - Building line maps (blueprints), circa 1876-1926; 10 volumes
      Not boxed.
  - T000236
    - Sanborn maps, circa 1873-1881; 81 maps
      Maps are oversize and mounted on board.